Preliminary Guide to the Appalachian Society of American Foresters Records, 1921-1999 and undated RL.00047
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Appalachian Society of American Foresters records
1921-1999 and undated
David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library
Appalachian Society of American Foresters
RL.00047
9 Linear Feet
Approximately 5209 Items
Access Restrictions
Collection is open for research.
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
All or portions of this collection may be housed off-site in Duke University's Library Service Center. The library may require up to 48 hours to retrieve these materials for research use.
Please contact Research Services staff before visiting the David M. Rubenstein Rare Book & Manuscript Library to use this collection.
Provenance
Acquired as a gift between 1986 and 1999.
Historical Note
A professional organization of foresters active in South Carolina, North Carolina, and Virginia. Formerly the Society of American Foresters - Appalachian Section.
Collection Overview
Newsletters, executive meeting minutes, directories, correspondence, election information, meeting critiques, and other printed matter document the activities of the Appalachian Society of American Foresters between 1921-1994. Records found in the collection include position descriptions, committee charters, by-laws, and copies of the organization's journal, Trail Blazer. There is also a report on the recovery from Hurricane Hugo (1989).
Forests and forestry -- Southern States; Timber -- Southern States; Forest management -- United States; Forests and forestry -- United States-History; Appalachian Society of American Foresters -- History; Appalachian Society of American Foresters
- Alphabetical Files Series, 1921-1999 and undated, 8 boxes
  - A-Ach (Box 1)
  - Ann-B (Box 2)
  - Com-Cor (Box 3)
  - Cor-D (Box 4)
  - F-Mem (Box 5)
  - N-Old (Box 6)
  - Pol-Tra (Box 7)
  - Ung-Work (Box 8)
- Professional Papers Series, 1958-1975 and undated, 2 boxes
  - Correspondence (Box 9)
  - Executive Committee minutes (Box 9)
  - Annual Meeting proceedings, 1958-1975 (Box 10)
- Accession (11-24-86), 1984-1986 and undated, 2 folders
  Scope and Contents note
  Contains minutes and conference proceedings.
- Accession (88-095), 1986-1988 and undated, 1 box
  Consists of correspondence, meeting minutes and pamphlets.
- Accession 91-154, 1977-1989 and undated, 2 boxes
  Chiefly contains issues of The Trail Blazer, various other publications, and meeting minutes.
- Accession (93-101), 1 box
  Contains correspondence, bylaws, minutes, ASAF directory of leadership and position descriptions.
- Accession (1998-0309), 1989-1994 and undated, 1 box
  Contains minutes of Executive Committee meetings and annual business meetings as well as leadership directories.
- Accession (1999-0239), 4 boxes
  - Minutes -- Executive Committee Meetings, 1983-1990 (Box 1)
  - APSAF position statements (Box 1)
  - Correspondence, 1985-1998 (Box 1)
  - Charters (Box 1)
  - Ad Hoc Dues Increase Committee, 1992 (Box 1)
  - APSAF Elections, 1972-1998 (Box 2)
  - Directory, 1983-1999 (Box 2)
  - Meeting Guides (Box 3)
  - Annual Meeting Critique, 1982-1998 (Box 3)
  - Summer Meetings, 1984-1999 (Box 3)
  - 100 Years of Professional Forestry, 1992 (Box 3)
  - Second Regional Technical Conference, 1984 (Box 3)
  - Third Regional Technical Conference, 1985 (Box 3)
  - Fourth Regional Technical Conference, 1986 (Box 3)
  - Hurricane Hugo: Recovering from Disaster, 1993 [Hurricane Hugo, 1989] (Box 3)
  - Forestry Source newspaper (Box 3)
  - Minutes of the New Executive Committee, 1995-1998 (Box 4)
- Accession (2013-0062), 1985-2005, 3 boxes
  This series includes APSAF charters, leadership directories with conact information for various members, information on elections, reports from the Executive Committee, and correspondence.
  - Elections, 1987-1988 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Elections, 2004 (Box 1)
  - APSAF Charters, 2001 & 2003 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 1999 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 2000 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 2001 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 2002 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 2003 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 2004 (Box 1)
  - Directory of Leadership, 2005 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1985 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1986 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1987 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1988 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1989 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1990 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1991 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1992 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1993 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1994 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1995 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1996 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1997 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1998 (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 1999 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2000 (2 folders) (Box 1)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2001 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2002 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2003 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2004 (Box 2)
  - Executive Committee Minutes, 2005 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 1999 (Box 2)
  - Correspondence, 2000 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2001 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2002 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2003 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, 2004 (Box 3)